<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Emulation on xkevio&#39;s homepage</title>
    <link>/tags/emulation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Emulation on xkevio&#39;s homepage</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/emulation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Emulation, Typesetting, Ricing Linux and more...</title>
      <link>/posts/website-redesign/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/website-redesign/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Between the last time I edited this website / blog / homepage and now, quite a few things in my life have changed &amp;ndash; my general interests however have stayed the same with a few new additions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am still very much into developing emulators (with some downtime here and there) and even worked on a new one for the Game Boy Advance, partially also for my &lt;a href=&#34;../thesis.pdf&#34;&gt;bachelor&amp;rsquo;s thesis&lt;/a&gt;. This introduced me to a little bit of Just-in-Time compilation via &lt;a href=&#34;https://cranelift.dev&#34;&gt;cranelift&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; which was both a great source of frustration but also fun and learning. The JIT part of my GBA emulator is far from finished, and I should really get back to it as I don&amp;rsquo;t know anyone who has used cranelift for emulation yet, but at the very least the general interpreter is done and many games work, even those using &lt;em&gt;Mode 7&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Game Boy (DMG-01) Emulation</title>
      <link>/posts/gameboy-emulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/gameboy-emulation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a few months but my Game Boy emulator is all but finished &amp;ndash; or at least ready to be published.&#xA;Now, for people following me on GitHub it has been available the entire time but now I am at a point where&#xA;most major features are implemented, plus a few extras, and the UI is presentable!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since I wrote the entire thing in Rust with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.egui.rs/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;egui&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;code&gt;eframe&lt;/code&gt; as my backend, I was able to quite simply&#xA;compile it to WASM using &lt;a href=&#34;https://trunkrs.dev/&#34;&gt;Trunk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
